Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Students for a Free Tibet Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008 - ongoing; Students for a Free Tibet.
  Students for a Free Tibet (SFT), founded in 1994, is a student run activist group working in solidarity with the Tibetan people for human rights and freedom. The organization uses education, advocacy, and nonviolent direct action with the goal of achieving Tibetan independence and political freedom. The group has grown internationally, with 650 high school, university and community chapters.
  Human rights |z Tibet (China).; Students--Political activity.; Tibet (China)
- Students for a New American Politics Archived Website, Feb 15, 2010- ongoing; Students for a New American Politics
  Students for a New American Politics (SNAP) is a student-run political action committee, founded in 2005. The mission of SNAP is to elect progressive candidates and train students to become progressive leaders in the future. The organization trains college students, recent graduates, and college-age youth to serve as SNAP Fellows, full-time field organizers for Congressional candidates.
  Political action committees |z United States.; Students--Political activity--United States.
- Students for Free Culture Archived Website, Jul 7, 2011-Jul 5, 2013; Students for Free Culture
  Students for Free Culture (SFC) is a non-partisan group of students and young people who work to get their peers involved in the free culture movement, a movement that promotes the freedom to distribute and modify creative works in the form of free content by using the Internet and other forms of media.. SFC chapters exist at over 40 colleges and universities around the world. Students for Free Culture was founded by two Swarthmore students after they sued voting-machine manufacturer Diebold for abusing copyright law in 2003. SFC has collaborated with Creative Commons, the Electronic Frontier Foundation, Public Knowledge, Downhill Battle, and other free software and media reform groups.
  Copyright; Freedom of information.; Student movements.
- Students for Sensible Drug Policy (SSDP) Archived Website, Feb 19, 2012- ongoing; Students for a Sensible Drug Policy
  Students for a Sensible Drug Policy (SSDP), founded in 1998, is an international network of students concerned with the impact of drug abuse has on communities and against the War on Drugs policies. SSDP uses student mobilization and civic engagement to change the drug war policies. The website contains a chapters list, a news blog, a campaigns page, events listings, a video and photograph gallery, and a resources page.
  Drugs |x Law and legislation |z United States.; Student movements |z United States.
- Students Over Banks Archived Website, Nov 8, 2011-May 8, 2013; Campus Progress
  Students Over Banks is a Campus Progress campaign aimed at supporting President Obama’s plan to make college more affordable for Americans. The President’s plan would end wasteful subsidies to student loan companies by generating all new federal loans from the existing Direct Lending Program, and using the $87 billion in savings to provide more education grants for low and middle income families. Students Over Banks gives young people a means to support the bill. Students Over Banks, and its parent organization Campus Progress works to make college more affordable and accessible for all young people.
  Access to higher education |z United States.; College students |x Political activity |z United States.; Student movements |z United States.
- Students United for a Free CUNY Archived Website, Apr 25, 2012-Oct 24, 2014; Students United for a Free CUNY
  Students United for a Free CUNY is a student group working to make the City University of New York university system free for all. The website contains a campus listing, news, multimedia, and resources.
  Student movements |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Students Working for Equal Rights Archived Website, Nov 5, 2011- ongoing; Students Working for Equal Rights
  Students Working for Equal Rights (SWER) is a student-run chapter organization, founded by undocumented youth, working for social justice and equal access to education through organizing, political education, alliance building, nonviolent direct action and civic engagement.
  Immigrant youth |z United States.; Student movements |z United States.
- Surveillance Camera Players Archived Website, Jul 27, 2011; Surveillance Camera Players
  Founded in 1996 in New York city to protest the use of surveillance cameras in public places, SCP performed specially adapted plays directly in front of these cameras. The group does not appear to have been active since 2009.
  Theater |x Political aspects.; Theatrical companies |z New York (State) |z New York.; Video surveillance.
- Take Back the Night Archived Website, Jul 25, 2012- ongoing; Take Back the Night Foundation
  The Take Back the Night Foundation, founded in 2001, serves to create safe communities and respectful relationships through awareness events and initiatives. They work to end sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence, sexual abuse and all other forms of sexual violence. TBTN works with survivors in their healing process. The website contains event listings and resources.
  Domestic Violence |x prevention & control.
- Take Back the Strand Archived Website, May 9, 2012-Aug 6, 2013; Take Back the Strand
  Take Back the Strand is the website for the Local UAW 2179, the Strand Bookstore Employees Union in lower Manhattan. The union works to regain its contract that was lost in September 2011. The website contains news, action alerts, and other articles.
  Publishers and publishing |x Employees |x Labor unions.
- Take Back WBAI Radio Archived Website, May 6, 2011- Nov 5, 2013; Coalition to Take Back WBAI
  The Coalition to Take Back WBAI is a group of WBAI listeners, staff, and activist organizations that believe that New York 's diverse communities should control WBAI radio network. The Coalition to Take Back WBAI believes that the leadership of Interim Executive Director of Pacifica, Grace Aaron has been a detriment to the WBAI radio station and calls for Aaron’s departure and believes that Pacifica is supporting his administration.
  WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.).; Alternative radio broadcasting |z United States.
- Take The Square Archived Website, Oct 8, 2011- ongoing; Take the Square
  Take the Square, established in 2011, is a global network of camping in city centers to demonstrate against a dominant and oppressive system, lead by a political class working for banks and big corporations and as a way to promote new initiatives of political, social, economical, artistic and cultural organization. The website contains updated information about the movement, news, analysis, a manual to spread the movement, videos, photos, a calendar with the most important events worldwide, and contact information of all groups in the network. The website is affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement.
- Talking Points Memo Archived Website, Oct 15, 2013- ongoing; Talking Points Memo.
  Talking Points Memo is the flagship blog of TPM Media LLC, which also publishes TPMmuckraker, TPMDC, TPMtv and TPMCafe. Founder and editor Josh Marshall began publishing Talking Points Memo during the 2000 Florida vote recount. The site specializes in original reporting on government and politics and offers breaking news coverage, investigative reporting, high profile guest bloggers and a book club. In addition to many other awards and citations, TPM was the first online news organization to win thr George Polk Award in 2008.
  News web sites |z United States.; United States |x Politics and government |v Newspapers.
- Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University. Archived Website, May 7, 2008, Jul 27, 2009 - ongoing; Tamiment Library.
  The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at New York University form a unique, internationally-known center for scholarly research on Labor and the Left. The primary focus is the complex relationship between trade unionism and progressive politics and how this evolved over time. Archival, print, photograph, film, and oral history collections describe the history of the labor movement and how it related to the broader struggle for economic, social, and political change. In 1977 the Robert F. Wagner Archives was established as a joint program of the New York City Central Labor Council and the Tamiment Library. The Wagner is the designated repository for the records of the Council's more than 200 member unions. Today the Library has an extraordinary research collection documenting the history of organized labor in New York and the workers who built the City. Tamiment has one of the finest research collections in the country documenting the history of radical politics: socialism, communism, anarchism, utopian experiments, the cultural left, the New Left, and the struggle for civil rights and civil liberties. It is the repository for the Archives of Irish America, the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives, and a growing Asian American labor collection.
- Tar Sands Blockade Archived Website, Jan 10, 2013- ongoing; Tar Sands Blockade
  Tar Sands Blockade is a coalition of affected Texas and Oklahoma residents and organizers using nonviolent direct action to physically stop the Keystone XL tar sands pipeline. The website contains information about profiteers to the pipeline, action alerts, promotional tools, and news postings.
  Environmentalism |z United States.; Fossil fuels |x Environmental aspects |z United States.; Keystone XL Pipeline Project.
- Tax Evaders Archived Website, Apr 30, 2013; Tax Evaders
  Tax Evaders is an educational video game, designed after the class arcade game Space Invaders. In this version, the invaders are large corporations, including Bank of America, GE, Pfizer, Microsoft, Goldman Sachs, and other large banks and corporations. The website uses the game to educate players on the tax cuts provided by the government to these corporations. The website calls for a tax reform and shows statistics on corporate tax cuts and evasions through offshore accounts. The website contains the game, statistics, and a blog.
  Corporate accountability.; Social responsibility of business.; Video games--Parodies, imitations, etc.--Comic books, strips,
- Teachers for a Just Contract Archived Website, May 4, 2011-Aug 2, 2012; Teachers for a Just Contract
  Teachers for a Just Contract is a New York City base organization that works to improve the working conditions of teachers by struggling for the vigorous enforcement of their collective bargaining agreement, particularly in relation to disciplinary actions, harassment and job security. In addition they work to fight school overcrowding and protect their professional autonomy.
  United Federation of Teachers.; Teachers' contracts--United States.; Teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Tenants Political Action Committee Archived Website, Mar 3, 2012 - ongoing; Tenants Political Action Committee
  Tenants Political Action Committee is a PAC that helps preserve and protect affordable housing for tenants in New York. Tenants PAC endorses candidates who are strong supporters of tenants' rights and gives renters more power with elected officials. The website contains news, endorsements, campaigns, and event listings.
- TERRANODE Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011-Mar 6, 2014; Transnational Temps
  Terranode, created by Fred Adam, Andy Deck, Mi Jin Park, Veronica Perales, Alex Spyropoulos, Stewart Ziff, is a collaborative project that explores tactical media, relating art and social activism. Through art, they work to raise awareness of environmental issues, like global warming. The website contains web art projects, proposals for future projects, and other links. The website has had very little activity since 2007.
- Theater for the New City Archived Website, Oct 6, 2011- ongoing; Theater for the New City
  Theater for the New City, founded in 1971 and known familiarly as "TNC", is one of New York City's leading Off-Off-Broadway theaters, known for radical political plays and community commitment. Productions at TNC have won 43 Obie Awards and the Pulitzer Prize for Drama. TNC currently exists as a 4-theater complex in a 30,000-square-foot (2,800 m2) space located at 155 1st Avenue, in Manhattan's East Village.
  Theatrical companies |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Theatre of the Oppressed Archived Website, May 6, 2012-; Theatre of the Oppressed
  The International Theatre of the Oppressed, founded in 1971 by Augusto Boal in Brazil, is a theatre technique that uses theatre as means of promoting social and political change, through the use of audience participation. The website contains a listing of theater groups that use the technique, news, and a library.
  Theater |x Political aspects.
- The Buckeye Socialist Alternative Archived Website, May 5, 2011-Nov 5, 2012; Solidarity (Organization: U.S.).
  THE DAN LA Botz Socialist for Senate campaign in Ohio represents an important success in the recent context of leftist third party initiatives. Running the first Socialist Party campaign for national office in Ohio since 1936, La Botz garnered 25,368 votes statewide, one of the more successful socialist electoral bids in decades. Information on the campaign is found on Solidarity's website.
  Socialism |z Ohio.
- The Day We Fight Back: Feb 11, 2014, Feb 11, 2014-ongoing; Access; Demand Progress; Electronic Frontier Foundation; Fight for the Future and Center for Rights.; Free Press
  The Day We Fight Back is a mobilization on February 11, 2014, sponsored by Access, Electronic Frontier Foundation, Demand Progress, ACLU, and other organizations, in opposition to the National Security Agency's mass spying. The campaign also is honoring the memory of Aaron Swartz and the successful campaign against the Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA).
  Freedom of information.; Internet |x Law and legislation |z United States.
- The Design Studio for Social Intervention Archived Website, Jun 1, 2011- ongoing; Design Studio for Social Intervention
  DS4SI (Design Studio for Social Intervention) is dedicated to changing how social justice is imagined, developed and deployed here in the United States. We are creating a design studio for the progressive arm of the nonprofit sector in order to support the sector’s ability to create new forms of effective social intervention and the exploration of new ways to be interventionists. We believe that creating a space for design and intentionally supporting the development of a sector-specific design practice is imperative in order for the sector to break out of its box of exhausted forms. In so doing, we will liberate our vision, invigorate our spirit and be able to take the greatest possible advantage of this moment.
  Design |x Political aspects |z United States; Social justice |z United States.
- The Feminist Theory Website: English Introduction Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011-Jul 25, 2013; Switala, Kristin
  The Feminist Theory Website provides research materials and information for students, activists, and scholars interested in women's conditions and struggles around the world. The goals of this website are: 1) to encourage a wide range of research into feminist theory, and 2) to encourage dialogue between women (and men) from different countries around the world. Hopefully, this will result in new connections, new ideas, and new information about feminist theory and women's movements. The Feminist Theory Website has three parts: 1) various fields within feminist theory; 2) different national / ethnic feminisms; and 3) individual feminists. All of these parts are updated and expanded regularly. To access these pages, please click on the buttons in the left column.
  Feminism.; Feminists.
- The Fugs Archived Website, Jul 13, 2010- ongoing; Fugs (Musical group).
  The Fugs, a group of poet-musicians, was founded in New York City’s East Village in early 1965 by Ed Sanders, Ken Weaver, and Tuli Kupferberg (1923-2010). The band is a folk rock group whose song lyrics were informed by an anti-authoritarian, anti-war, bohemian sensibility. They have performed and issued albums for the last 35 years. This website is the band’s official webpage.
  Beat generation |z New York (State) |z New York.; Folk-rock music |z New York (State) |z New York.; Protest songs--United States.
- The Funniest Signs From The Rally To Restore Sanity And/Or Fear! Archived Website, Nov 13, 2010-Jan 20, 2012; Katla McGlynn, in The Huffington Post
  On October 30, 2010 TV personalities and news satirists Jon Stewart and Stephan Colbert hosted a rally in Washington D.C. called Rally To Restore Sanity And/Or Fear. These captures are of some of the signs held at the rally by participants.
  Political satire.
- The Groundswell Collective Archived Website, Nov 16, 2009-Feb 15, 2014; Groundswell Collective.
  The Groundswell Collective, founded in 2006, is a loose affiliation of artists that work at the intersection of art and activism. The collective is interested in how art relates to social movements and to use of the creativity of the radical left to create an impact in society. The collective uses various different media and the website maintains a blog, catalogs art and runs an online store and barter network.
  Art |x Political aspects |z United States.
- The Huffington Post Archived Website, Nov 20, 2010- ongoing; Huffington Post.com, Inc.
  The Huffington Post is a liberal/progressive American news website and content aggregating blog founded by Arianna Huffington.
  Huffington, Arianna Stassinopoulos, 1950-; Electronic newspapers.; News web sites |z United States.
- The Icarus Project Archived Website, May 8, 2011 - ongoing; Icarus Project
  The Icarus Project, founded in 2002, is a support community designed to create a network of people living with and/or affected by experiences diagnosed in the contemporary language as Bipolar, Manic-Depressive, or other psychiatric conditions. The website provides an outlet for people who want to view their conditions as “gifts” as opposed to a disease or disorder. The website contains information on their support network, art shows, articles, and a blog.
  Mental illness |x Alternative treatment.; Mental illness--Moral and ethical aspects; Mentally ill--Civil rights
- The Militant Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009- ongoing; The Militant (New York, N.Y.: 1941)
  This site contains articles from the Militant newspaper, a socialist newsweekly published in the interests of working people. The Militant is associated with the Socialist Workers Party, a U.S. Trotskyist organization.
  Socialist Workers Party.; Socialism |z United States |v Periodicals.; Trotskyism |z United States.
- The Multitude Archived Website, Feb 26, 2012-Aug 24, 2012; TheMultitude.org
  The Multitude is a discussion forum designed to help Occupy Wall Street protesters organize and formally communicate online. The website contains three main areas of interest, planning, movement philosophy, and reform. The website ceased to exist in summer 2012.
- The Nuclear Resister Archived Website, Jul 14, 2011- ongoing; The Nuclear Resister
  Initially founded in 1980, The Nuclear Resister is a news source that reports on nonviolent resistance to war and the nuclear threat. They publish a quarterly newsletter and blog.
- The Peace Pentagon Archived Website, Sep 26, 2009-Mar 9, 2010; Friends of 339
  The Peace Pentagon is the website for information on the building that houses multiple different peace organizations, including the War Resisters League, Paper Tiger Television, Deep Dish TV, Libertarian Book Club, A.J. Muste Memorial Institute, and Socialist Party. The website also represents the group Friends of 339, which is working to prevent the sale of the building. The building is located at 339 Lafayette Street.
  Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York.; Pacifists--New York (State)--New York.; Peace movements |z New York (State) |z New York.
- The Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press Archived Website, Dec 5, 2011- ongoing; Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press
  The Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press (RCFP) is an American nonprofit organization, founded in 1970, that provides free legal assistance to and on behalf of journalists. A number of prominent journalists presently sit on the organization's steering committee, including Dan Rather, and Judy Woodruff and, prior to his death, Walter Cronkite. Its offices are located in Arlington, Virginia.The RCFP actively aids in defending reporters facing subpoenas and court orders to disclose the identity of confidential sources. The Reporters Committee is also involved in a variety of First Amendment, shield law, freedom of information, and other free speech activities, including state open records and meetings law compliance. The organization publishes a quarterly magazine, The News Media and The Law. In addition, the Reporters Committee files legal briefs on a variety of issues that affect a journalist's ability to gather and disseminate news and also maintains a 24-hour legal defense hotline for journalists and media lawyers.
  Freedom of the press |z United States
- The Situationist International Text Library Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009- ongoing; Internationale situationniste.
  Situationist International Text Library is part of Nothingness.org, an anarchist and situationist website. The Library is an ongoing project of uploading pieces of Situationist-related literature. Entire books, lengthy articles, excerpts from the journals Potlatch and Internationale Situationniste, newspaper articles, and other files.
  Anarchism |v Sources.; Internationale situationniste.
- The Socialist Archived Website, Dec 1, 2013- ongoing; Socialist Party (U.S.).
  The Socialist magazine and website are published by members of the Socialist Party USA. The website contains information on the Socialist Party's platform, issues of the magazine, and articles.
  Socialism |z United States |v Periodicals.; Socialists |z United States.
- The Struggle for Free Speech at CCNY, 1931-42 Archived Website Archived Website, Jul 31, 2009; City University of New York. City College. Library.
  The Struggle for Free Speech at CUNY, 1931-1942, is a permanent online exhibition at the library of the City College of the City University of New York. This exhibit describes a series of events that took place at the City College of New York (the oldest of all CUNY colleges) during the 1930s and early 1940s that posed challenges to notions of academic freedom and civil liberties.
- The Trials of The Scottsboro Boys Archived Website, Aug 23, 2009; University of Missouri--Kansas City. School of Law
  This website is an archive dedicated to the Trials of the Scottsboro Boys, which was a set of trials, convictions, reversals, and retrials of an alleged gang rape of two white girls by nine black teenagers on a Southern Railroad freight run on March 25, 1931. The results of the trial opened southern juries to blacks, exacerbated sectional strife, and divided America's political left.
  African Americans |x Civil rights |z Alabama.; Scottsboro Trial, Scottsboro, Ala., 1931.
- The Yes Men Archived Website, May 8, 2010- ongoing; Yes Men (Activist group)